{
  "category": "Networking",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Which protocol does Ping use?",
      "options": [
        "ICMP",
        "IGMP",
        "UDP",
        "TCP"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "ICMP",
      "id": "F1A6DB4A-5C54-4DA5-AF6F-CFD9E19977F9"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the 'S' stand for in HTTPS?",
      "options": [
        "Secure",
        "Socket",
        "Service",
        "Session"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Secure",
      "id": "2E39810B-AC3B-479A-8955-E94D0E4EE383"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which device is used to segment a network into different broadcast domains?",
      "options": [
        "Hub",
        "Switch",
        "Router",
        "Repeater"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Router",
      "id": "7CBD4EB8-6819-4ABC-B0BD-5046883A545C"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the maximum length (in meters) of a UTP CAT5 cable in an Ethernet network?",
      "options": [
        "100",
        "120",
        "150",
        "200"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "100",
      "id": "4AC31D70-6EB2-4716-A005-658635FCB4B0"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the subnet mask for a network with a CIDR notation of /24?",
      "options": [
        "255.255.255.0",
        "255.255.0.0",
        "255.0.0.0",
        "255.255.255.255"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "255.255.255.0",
      "id": "EA810E8F-C19D-4C73-8713-E37CBDBC5033"
    },
    {
      "question": "In a network using IPv6, what is the size of an address in bits?",
      "options": [
        "32",
        "64",
        "128",
        "256"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "128",
      "id": "1D5F880D-21EE-492F-BE3F-91C311833963"
    },
    {
      "question": "In the OSI model, which layer is responsible for error-free data delivery with flow control, segmentation/desegmentation, and error checking?",
      "options": [
        "Network Layer",
        "Transport Layer",
        "Data Link Layer",
        "Session Layer"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Transport Layer",
      "id": "DFBA9D6D-5873-404D-8D57-42649C7540C4"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which protocol is used by DHCP to provide IP addresses automatically to hosts on a network?",
      "options": [
        "IP",
        "UDP",
        "TCP",
        "ICMP"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "UDP",
      "id": "80119CC4-7E2E-4A47-B41A-7A6605A86F94"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which routing protocol uses cost as its metric?",
      "options": [
        "OSPF",
        "RIP",
        "BGP",
        "IGRP"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "OSPF",
      "id": "38CF99A5-2510-40B4-AFE7-7AC6E2FDB495"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the primary function of a firewall in network security?",
      "options": [
        "Malware detection",
        "Controlling incoming and outgoing network traffic",
        "Data encryption",
        "Password protection"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Controlling incoming and outgoing network traffic",
      "id": "1D396602-55C7-45CA-96B4-CBD8B5EFF771"
    }
  ]
}
